Charles Tucker Barrett

ctbarrett.tech@gmail.com | 919-999-7792 | Raleigh, NC

Website: https://ctbarrett.tech

GitHub: https://github.com/GrinninBarrett | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tucker-barrett-10015645/

Results-driven web developer with a love for building beautiful, responsive, accessible web applications. Experienced working on collaborative teams, spontaneous problem-solving, and devising creative approaches to difficult situations. Interested in using technology to solve real-world problems to make our world a better place.

Technical Skills

Git / GitHub, Agile Development, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express, SQL, MySQL, JSON, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Applications Built

Skillet & Shaker | Contributing Developer | grinninbarrett.github.io/recipe-finder

- Team project using recipe APIs to find food and drink recipes | JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Repo: github.com/grinninbarrett/recipe-finder

Etch-a-Sketch | Sole Developer | grinninbarrett.github.io/etch-a-sketch

- Drawing canvas based on the famous Etch-a-Sketch | JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Repo: github.com/grinninbarrett/etch-a-sketch

Weather Dashboard | Sole Developer | grinninbarrett.github.io/weather-dashboard

- Gets local weather data using OpenWeather API | JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Repo: github.com/grinninbarrett/weather-dashboard

Wasted Class Time | Sole Developer | grinninbarrett.github.io/wasted-class-time

- Web app to track poor student behavior | JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Repo: github.com/grinninbarrett/wasted-class-time

Other Experience

VIPKID Online Teaching Platform - ESL Teacher - 2018 to present

- Set and maintain regular schedule of classes to teach English to Chinese students, ages 4-15
- Manage relationships with students and parents; successfully build and maintain positive rapport

South Harnett Elementary School, Bunnlevel, NC - Music Teacher - 2019 to 2021

- Develop a comprehensive, sequential music curriculum for grades 3-5 and K-5 special needs
- Create and implement detailed, student-centered lesson plans

Worwick Franklin Institute, Ulsan, South Korea - Homeroom Kindergarten Teacher - 2015 to 2018

- Taught English, math, art, and other subjects to kindergarten students in an English immersion environment
- Bridged language and cultural divides to collaborate with Korean coworkers

Leadership and Honors

- President, Phi Mu Alpha Sinfonia, Delta Sigma Chapter, Columbia, SC 2010 to 2011
- Drum Major, USC Marching Band, Columbia, SC 2009 to 2010
- President's and Dean's Lists, Multiple Recipient, University of South Carolina
- Eagle Scout, Boy Scouts of America, Troop 222, Abingdon, VA

Relevant Coursework

- Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python, MITx
- FreeCodeCamp Responsive Web Design Certification

Education

University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC - 2021

Certificate - JavaScript Full Stack Web Development

University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC - 2012

Bachelor of Music Education with Horn Performance Certificate